Dr. Christophe Dominique Marie Guéret

Linked Data researcher and open data advocate interested in the design of decentralised interconnected knowledge systems. Currently focusing on the interplay between Information and Communication Technologies for development (ICT4D) and Computer Science.

Office address Data Archiving and Networked Services

Anna van Saksenlaan 51, 2593 HW Den Haag, Netherlands

Phone: +31 61 45 76494

Online addresses Email: christophe.gueret@dans.knaw.nl

Homepage: http://christophe.gueret.me Tweets: https://twitter.com/cgueret and https://twitter.com/wwsemweb

Code: https://github.com/cgueret

Papers: http://www.mendeley.com/profiles/christophe-gueret/

Blogs: http://semweb4u.wordpress.com and http://www.worldwidesemanticweb.org

LinkedIn: http://nl.linkedin.com/in/cgueret

Personal details Languages spoken: French (mother tongue), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)

Date of Birth: December 11, 1979

Research Interests Decentralised information systems and ICT for development (ICT4D), Usage of Computational In-

telligence techniques to address Semantic Web problems. Network analysis of Complex Systems

applied to Web Data.

Competences

Development languages (Java, Javascript, Python, C, C++). Web-development and document Computer skills

specification languages (HTML, Javascript, CSS, XML, LATEX, RDF, SPARQL). Use of Windows,

Mac and GNU/Linux operating systems. Network administration.

Other skills and

Interests

Good presentation and communication skills, very motivated in learning new things and good at team work. Event organisation and chairing. Networking and community building.

Education

2002 - 2006PhD, Computer Science - University of Tours, France

Field of work: Data processing, P2P networks, Swarm algorithms

Disseration title: "Navigateurs Internet intelligents: Algorithmes de fourmis artificielles pour la

diffusion d'informations dans un réseau P2P

Laboratory: Computer science laboratory of Tours (LI), research team "HaNT"

Advisors: Pr. Mohamed Slimane, Dr. Nicolas Monmarché

2001 - 2002Master Degree, Computer Science - University of Tours, France

Field of work: Virtual 3D landscape representation, Data streaming

1999 - 2002Engineer, Computer science applied to Industry - University of Tours, France

Experiences

Professional Experience

Oct 2012 - Present

DANS/KNAW - Den Haag Position : Researcher

- Sept 2013 present : Co-leader of the WG on "Data curation and navigation based on knowledge maps" in KNOWeSCAPE (http://knowescape.org/).
- 2012 present: Co-lead the e-Humanities project "CEDAR" on historical Dutch census data (see http://www.cedar-project.nl/ and http://ehumanities.nl/).
- · 2012 2013: Lead the project "ERS" about entity registries for low-connectivity contexts under a grant from Verisign Inc. together with the ExaScale InfoLab (see http: //worldwidesemanticweb.org/projects/entity-registries/).

Oct 2007 - Aug 2012

Knowledge Representation & Reasoning Group (Al Dept.) - Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam

Position : Post-doctoral researcher

- Until 2010, lead the SOKS project investigating cross-research opportunities between Computational Intelligence and the Semantic Web (http://www.few.vu.nl/soks/).
- From 2010, Work package leader for the activities from the VUA in the European funded (FP7) LATC project providing support for publishing Linked Data on the Web (http:// latc-project.eu/).
- Wide "World • In 2011, launched the Semantic Web" portal worldwidesemanticweb.org) and the W3C community group "Development Linked Data (DLD)" (http://www.w3.org/community/dld/). Still currently manages both groups together with like-minded researchers.

Teaching Experience

2012 - present Vriie Univeristeit Amsterdam, Netherlands

Position: Guest researcher Guest lecture in the "Environment & Development" course of the Faculty of Social Sciences to speak about low-resource ICT infrastructures. Lecturer in the "ICT4D" master module. Supervision of Master and Bachelor students on ICT4D related topics.

2008 - 2012Vrije Univeristeit Amsterdam, Netherlands

Position : PostDoc

Guest lecture in the "Automated Reasoning" course to explain how to solve CSPs with evolutionary computing. Lecturer in the "ICT4D" master module. Supervision of Master and Bachelor students

Committees and reviews

2014 Semantic Web journal (SWJ)

Position: Guest editor

Journal of Systems and Software, Journal of Web Semantics (JWS), Semantic Web journal 2007 - present

(SWJ), IEEE Internet Computing, Journal On Advances in Internet Technology

2003 - present Workshops (Natures, SOAT, DownScale), Conferences (JFT, ESWC), Tutorials (LATC, LD4D,

KR4D)

Position: Member of Organizing Committee, Chair

ESWC, WWW, ISWC, EMERGING, GraphQ, LWDM, ATC, SOCINFO, MAJESTIC 2009 - present

Position: Member of Program Committee

Selected side activities

Sept 2013 - present Land Portal http://landportal.info/

Position: Member of Technical Architecture Group (TAG)

Contribute experience on system architecture and knowledge representation best practices for

publishing information about land usage.

July 2011 - present W3C http://w3c.org/

Position: W3C AC representative for the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, member of the W3C Work-

ing Group "Data on the Web Best Practices Working Group (dwbp)"

Contribute to creating standards for the Web

2010 - present OLPC http://wiki.laptop.org and SugarLabs https://www.sugarlabs.org/

Position: Community member

Contribute developing software, ideas and relations within the community

Selected publications

The full list of over 60 publications is available online: http://www.mendeley.com/profiles/christophe-gueret/

- [1] GUÉRET, Christophe; CUDRÉ-MAUROUX, Philippe: The Entity Registry System: Publishing and Consuming Linked Data in Poorly Connected Environments. In: *ERCIM News* (2014), April, 54–55. http://ercim-news.ercim.eu/en97/ri/the-entity-registry-system-publishing-and-consuming-linked-data-in-poorly-connected-environments
- [2] GUERET, Christophe; BOER, Victor de; SCHLOBACH, Stefan: Let's "Downscale" Linked Data. In: IEEE Internet Computing 18 (2014), Nr. 2, 70-73. http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/MIC.2014.29. - DOI 10.1109/MIC.2014.29. - ISSN 1089-7801
- [3] GUÉRET, Christophe; SCHLOBACH, Stefan; BOER, Victor D.; BON, Anna; AKKERMANS, Hans: Is data sharing the privilege of a few? Bringing Linked Data to those without the Web. In: Proceedings of ISWC2011 Outrageous ideas track (2011), S. 1-4. - Best paper award
- [4] GUÉRET, Christophe; GROTH, Paul; STADLER, Claus; LEHMANN, Jens: Assessing Linked Data Mappings using Network Measures. In: Proceedings of ESWC2012, 2012. - Nominated for best paper award
- [5] GUÉRET, Christophe; WANG, Shenghui; GROTH, Paul; SCHLOBACH, Stefan: Multi-scale Analysis of the Web Of Data: A Challenge to the Complex System's Community. In: Advances in Complex Systems 14 (2011), Nr. 04, 587. http://dx.doi. org/10.1142/S0219525911003153. - DOI 10.1142/S0219525911003153. - ISSN 0219-5259